Jack: One of the ways to communicate
effectively is to tailor the
communication to the audience.
If done correctly it should result in
engaging the audience with good results.
In business communication will involve
people at different levels of ability and
understanding, some may be colleagues who
understand what is being communicated,
some may be customers who might not be
fully conversant and need to be informed.
There are also different channels of
communication that must be considered
when communicating to different
audiences, from giving out information
generally, via social media or contacting
individuals directly via email.
Leah: Adapting communication style can
depend on whether the communication and
interaction is face to face or digital.
In person communication gives
the opportunity to observe body
language and can help in deciding
if a change of tone is needed.
The tone should also suit the audience,
respecting their views and not
being too preachy or condescending.
Over email or digital communication,
the message should be more
considered to be able to put it
across clearly and concisely.
Jack: Working with a team and presenting
ideas face to face, will give opportunity
for interaction and active listening
and the opportunity for feedback,
questioning and further discussion.
Vocabulary used should always fit
the audience the communication
is aimed at, and any complex
elements should be explained in
a way that others can understand.